Bhawna Agarwal

Product Designer with 6 years of formal design education, and 5+ years of experience designing and shipping well-crafted, high-impact experiences in the industry. I specialize in applying product thinking to break down complex problems and craft helpful experiences.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Product Designer, Wish

January 2021-Present, Full-time | San Francisco

- Leading design for Wish's Shopping Cart in a fast-paced, data-driven environment
- · Collaborating closely with cross-functional partners and stakeholders
- · Influencing peers and leadership to focus on user needs
- Led design for Wish Local pickup programs. Shipped several key projects including one with a large scope and ambiguous requirements.
- Demonstrated initiative by contributing to Wish's design system, and leading design for search filters for the Wish shopping app

UX Designer, Microsoft

April 2018-July 2019, Full-time | Hyderabad, India

- · Sole designer for Microsoft's Azure Backup product (Enterprise software)
- Collaborated with 10+ product managers over multiple projects to deliver experiences for the Azure Backup service
- Owned the design, and delivered end-to-end experiences for Backup Center in close collaboration with PMs, engineers, and the Azure UX team

UX Designer, Postman API Platform

June 2016-December 2017, Full-time | Bangalore, India

- Joined as the 21st employee, and reported to the CEO
- Applied extensive product thinking to envision, craft, and ship 6+ core projects within one year working as the Design Lead (sole designer), providing productivity gains to 15 million+ users
- Pitched a more usable and extensible Data Editor component proposal to executive leadership, got buy-in, and worked closely with a developer to ship the new editor
- Wore multiple hats provided customer support, and wrote product copy and feature marketing blog posts

Earlier experiences

- UX Designer, Housing.com, Full-time | June-December 2015
- UX Design Intern, HCII, Carnegie Mellon University | May-July 2014
- UX Design Intern, Robert Bosch | May–July 2013

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Masters in Information

IIT Guwahati, India

Bachelor of Design with Minor in Computer Science

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Publications in ACM digital library as first author
- First position in OzCHI 2014 –
 International student design challenge
- · S.N. Bose Scholar

SKILLS

UX Research	Software
and Design	Figma
Contexual Inquiry	Sketch
User Interviews	Principle
Persona Building	Invision
Writing Job Stories	Photoshop
Info. Architecture	Illustrator
Heuristic Evaluation	InDesign
Usability Testing	Tableau
Wireframing	
Mobile Design	Coding
Visual/UI Design	HTML/ CSS
Prototyping	Javascript
UX Writing	jQuery
Storytelling	Python

PORTFOLIO

bhawna2109.github.io/